Guide to the Grace Estelle Fox Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Grace Estelle Fox Papers
1925-1970.
Fox, Grace Estelle, 1899-1984.
55 items, (2 boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4078369
This collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, photographs, course-related materials and printed material of historian and professor Grace Estelle Fox, 1899-1984, (M.A., Columbia, 1925; PhD, 1938).
Biographical Note
Historian (Columbia M.A., 1925; Ph.D. 1938).
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, notes, photographs, course-related materials and printed materials consisting largely of manuscripts of Miss Fox's books, most notably, "Britain and Japan, 1858-1883," and four shorter articles dealing with topics in 19th and 20th century history. The small amount of correspondence deals almost exclusivley with her research on Japan. A few course outlines are the product of her years of teaching at Sarah Lawrence College, which she left in 1935 to accept a position with the U.S. State Department.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in five series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Manuscripts
Series III: Course-related Materials
Series IV: Photographs and Negatives
Series V: Printed Materials
Correspondence arranged alphabetically; manuscripts by title.
Subjects
Japan--History--19th century.; China--History--19th century.; Great Britain--Foreign relation--19th century.; Historians
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1985 Papers Whittlesey, Mrs. Charles R. Gift
- Series I: Correspondence
  - A-M (Box 1)
  - N-Z (Box 1)
- Series II: Manuscripts
  - "The Anglo-Japanese Convention of 1854" typed manuscript article (Box 1)
  - "Britain and Japan" typed manuscript monograph (Box 1)
  - "British Admirals and Chinese Pirates: 1832-1869" typed manuscript carbon copy of thesis 1 (Box 1)
  - "British Admirals and Chinese Pirates: 1832-1869" typed manuscript carbon copy of thesis 2 (Box 1)
  - "The British Press and the Japanese Press Laws" typed manuscript footnotes (Box 1)
  - "The British Press in Japan: 1861-1883" typed manuscript article (Box 1)
  - "Civil Rights in the German Totalitarian State" (Box 1)
  - "Elements of Nationalism in Three English Journals: 1850-1856" typed manuscript M.A. thesis, 2 copies. (Box 2)
  - "Ernest Mason Satow" typed manuscript article (Box 2)
  - "Hitler's Bill of Rights" typed manuscript article (Box 2)
  - "Joseph Mazzini: 1805-1872" typed manuscript article (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 2)
  - Notes - 14 envelopes of autographed manuscript notes on diverse topics (Box 2)
  - Outline "Tentative Plan for Book on the Role of the British Admiralty in Opening up of Japan" typed manuscript (Box 2)
  - Outline "Civil Rights in German Occupied Belgium & Northern France" (Box 2)
  - Outline "Project I - British Admirals and Chinese Pirates: 1832-1869" (Box 2)
  - Outline "Project II - History of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration" (Box 2)
  - Outline "Project III - Women Domestic Workers in Washington, D.C., 1940" (Box 2)
  - Outline "The Wife of Ching Yih" (Box 2)
  - "The Response of Ten English Journals to Lord Durham's Report" typed manuscript article, 2 copies. (Box 2)
  - "Sir Harry Smith Parkes" typed manuscript article (Box 2)
- Series III: Course-related Materials
  - Course outline for "Development & Significance of Nationalsim" (Box 2)
  - Course outline for "The New World" (Box 2)
- Series IV: Photographs and Negatives
  - Photographs and negatives (4) (Box 2)
- Series V: Printed Materials
  - Printed Materials by Grace Fox (Box 2)
  - Printed Materials, Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Printed Materials, Reviews of Books by Grace Fox (Box 2)